Robin Peng MSc, BA, DA

626-747-2136 | Irvine, CA robinpeng.dataanalysis@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

Master of Business & Science, a dedicated Data Specialist with 3 years' experience including Digital Platform, Data Lifecycle Management as well as Data Visualization in Social Media, Health and Medical Device Market. Apart from possessing exceptional analytical & problem-solving skills, Robin is a great team player with excellent communication and presentation skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Language: Advanced SQL, Python, Advanced Excel, VBA, REST API

Business Intelligence & Application: Power BI, Tableau, Salesforce,

Databases & Tools: Azure SQL DB, Snowflake, Databricks, ServiceNow, Jira, draw.io

EXPERTISE

✓ Digital Platform

✓ Data API Configuration

✓ Dashboard & Reporting

✓ Data Cleansing, Data Gap Analysis

- ✓ Business & Functional Requirement
- ✓ Social Media, Digital Marketing
- ✓ Biology, Medical Device Marketing
- ✓ CRM Analyses, Campaign Design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Premier Partner Experience Specialist | Meta

Jun 2022-present

- Conduct Digital Platform end to end customer/partner centric analyses including requirement collection, design, configuration, data analyses, troubleshooting, dashboard creation and presentation
- Work closely with internal & external stakeholders in terms of workflow, solutions, issues, features and insight
- Created monthly insight dashboard with summarized platform usage and partner issues to improve support workflow on enhancement of partner experience, and helped customer achieving 30% target gain
- Daily client facing activities in REST API troubleshooting, Dashboard delivery and presentation to partners

Senior Engagement Specialist | Seres Therapeutics.

Jun 2021-Jun 2022

- Worked on a medicine program including donor data collection, donor identification, qualification, engagement and management in a predictive way using statistical analysis
- Created lead, planed campaign and identified donors in Salesforce to maintain the relationships; developed engagement opportunities by analyzing donors' behavior; produced Tableau dashboard for payment review
- Strategic planning on donor candidate retention and recognition inactive donors through predictive analyses, which increase efficiency by 40%

ACDEMAIC PROJECT

Graduate Consultant | Covenant Health Network

Feb 2021-May 2021

- Built dashboard using Power BI and pulled data from CMS to provide facilities with real-time quality metrics
- Maintained and prepared data transformation in access database for queries, reporting and analysis needs.

Market Research Consultant | Hologic Inc.

Sep 2020-May 2021

• Evaluated data collected for critical strategic decision prioritizing improvement area to grow the U.S. medical devices market share through competitor analysis to monitor and maximize customer retention

Business Development Intern | Quick Biology Inc.

Jun 2020 - Sep 2020

- Organized 3 years' data in customer SQL Server database; identified methods of converting potential customers
- Created surveys to understand customer satisfaction, potential need and feedback for company improvement

Business Analyst | California NanoSystems Institute

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019

- Researched on potential market capacity/opportunity for a new medical product through competition analysis
- Planned FDA approval process to speed up the marketization and showcase the unique feature of the product

EDUCATION

- Master of Business and Science, KECK GRADUATE INSTITUTE, Claremont, CA
- Sep 2019 May 2021
- Bachelor of Science in Neuroscience, MICHIGAN STATE UNIVERSITY, East Lansing, MI
- Aug 2015 May 2019